# RITUPARNA MOHANTY () Featured

Currently working as a MS-SQL DBA at Tata Consultancy Services from June 2016. Expertise in T-SQL writing stored procedures, triggers and functions. Administering SQL Server High Availability and Disaster Recovery strategies.



Current Designation: Sql Dba Administrator Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree:

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Incident Management, SQL, PLSQL, Oracle, SQL DBA, T-SQL, SQL Server Administration, Log Shipping

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### **Summary**

Currently working as a MS-SQL DBA at Tata Consultancy Services from June 2016. Expertise in T-SQL writing stored procedures, triggers and functions. Administering SQL Server High Availability and Disaster Recovery strategies. Expertise in Always-On Availability Groups (AAG) and HA/DR Troubleshooting. Expertise in Database Administration on Production Servers with server configuration, performance tuning and maintenance with outstanding troubleshooting capabilities.

## **Work Experience**

**Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.** as Sql Dba Administrator Jun 2016 to Till Date

- 1. McKinsey & Company (Management Consulting firm, Date: 2016-17)
- Worked on giving authentication to users using UNIX by creating schema for them.
- Worked as Production support engineer for handling ticket and incident management.
- 2. KPMG (Audit Company, Date: 2017-19)
- Worked as a SQL/PLSQL developer in an Audit firm project as well as gave L3 support on tickets, maintenance tasks and assigned projects to the next level group.
- Monitored and tuned database resources and activities for SQL Server databases.
- Designed, developed and maintained relational databases.
- Worked on the tool Retain International for managing and maintaining resources and their information.
- 3. Allianz Life (Insurance-based company, Date: 2019-Current)
- Served as support for database administration tasks including configuration management, backup/recovery, performance optimization, and space management.
- Assist developers with MS SQL Server issues and questions.
- Giving Production support as well on the databases and maintaining the application from backend.
- Having hands on experience in DR processes including Log Shipping and Database Mirroring.
- Proficiency and expertise in SQL Backup/Recovery, Disaster recovery and planning.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Institute of technical education and research in 2016

PG: in 0

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

The Complete Oracle SQL Certification

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
MS SQL	
PLSQL	

# **Languages Known**

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Odia	Expert			

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

**Employment Status: Full time**